## David Okoli

Ife, Osun, Nigeria



davidokolimail1@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/david-okoli-7423b0202

## **Summary**

I am a Front-end Web Developer and HealthCare Intern ,Competent at helping Clients/Businesses Create Goal achieving and elegant Web and Digital Experiences ,Over 1 Year in this Industry I prioritize good communication & time management ,application of expertise together with User and Client satisfaction to achieve the goal .

My Experiences ,Volunteering, Certifications, Achievements ,Honors and Skills are quite a handful and are detailed outside this summary section.

I also apply my skills in Development (HTML5,CSS and JavaScript), Design (Visual Design, color theory, typography, layout and navigation), User Experience (UX Design, UX writing, copywriting, Web accessibility, website performance Optimization), Branding, Digital marketing (Social, Email and SEO marketing), Writing(Content Writing) and Blogging for the purpose.

I ensure I engage with the community and recent trends and update my skills and experience with modern state of the art tools .

I am passionate about HealthCare (Preventive Medicine especially) and I help Healthcare Companies create and review Health content.

I take arts as an enjoyable engagement, so I engage in Creative writing and Poetry. I Rap and write songs. I write on the Nigerian Music Industry for publication.

## **Experience**



#### Intern

TurnTableCharts

Sep 2021 - Present (2 months +)

I help the team write articles on Nigerian Music and Entertainment



#### Social Committee(Sec)

Medical Students' Association, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife (IFUMSA)

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019 (1 year 1 month)

IFUMSA Social Committee ensures that students bond and have a good social life through sessions, The team ,The Director and I the Secretary were involved in ensuring a seamlessly easy and quality experience during our tenure. I engaged in Planning ,Designing and Event Planning with the team



#### Protocol Officer

Berts Production

Sep 2015 - Sep 2018 (3 years 1 month)

Berts Production was a pioneer modelling agency in the heart of Nigeria , I made sure there was a smooth running of regular periodic radio calls and photo shoot and handled some representation at Marketing Companies for the Agency

## IT Manager

**Berts Production** 

Sep 2015 - Sep 2018 (3 years 1 month)

Berts Production was a pioneer modelling agency in the heart of Nigeria, I made records and data clear and documented for ease of process for the agency.

#### Content Writer

Nigerian Medical Students' Association (NiMSA)

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018 (6 months)

NIMSA has a great hive of Student writers who are creative and good at writing .I wrote some articles worth reading and worried with other writers in the group.

## Member

Nigerian Red Cross Osun State Branch

Feb 2017 - Feb 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Nigerian Red Cross is the Nigerian Branch of the Red Cross Society notably renowned for their Paramilitary, Paramedic/Health/Emergency Medicine and Humanity contributions to the society of which I received some degree of training and education periodically while engaging in regular activities.

## Student Trainee

Ministry for Youth Development Abuja and Man'OWar .Citizenship and Leadership Training

Apr 2011 - Apr 2011 (1 month)

Sea School Citizenship and Leadership Training together with Man'O'War Training served as a paramilitary and Leadership training experience with challenging activities and learning points. I received a Certificate and a Man'O'War Badge in Honor of responsibility towards the training

#### **Education**



Pre-Degree Programme, Biology/Biological Sciences, General 2013 - 2014

# Loral International Secondary School Igbesa, Agbara Estate, Ogun State, Nigeria.

Secondary School Certificate, Biology/Biological Sciences, General 2006 - 2012

## Obafemi Awolowo University

Bachelor of Medicine, Bachelor of Surgery - MBBS, Medicine

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- **MordPress Ecommerce: WooCommerce** LinkedIn
- in Introduction to Web Design and Development LinkedIn
- Freelancing Foundations LinkedIn
- in WordPress 5 Essential Training LinkedIn
- Managing Your Small Business LinkedIn
- **MordPress 5 Essential Training: Site Administration** LinkedIn
- in Shopify Essential Training LinkedIn
- Personal Branding on Social Media LinkedIn
- in Learning Canva LinkedIn
- in Digital Marketing Foundations LinkedIn
- SEO Foundations LinkedIn
- Finance Essentials for Small Business LinkedIn
- Communication Foundations LinkedIn
- TIN HTML Essential Training LinkedIn
- in Design Aesthetics for the Web LinkedIn
- in User Experience for Web Design LinkedIn
- in Mapping the Modern Web Design Process LinkedIn

- in Illustrator for Web Design LinkedIn
- Tim CSS Essential Training LinkedIn
- Photoshop for Web Design LinkedIn
- Become a Web Designer LinkedIn
- in Time Management Fundamentals LinkedIn
- UX Writing Fundamentals Accenture
- Become a Copywriter Pro from ground up Eduonix Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd
- > Digital Skills : Digital Marketing Accenture
- **G** Start A Resume Google
- Leadership and Citizenship Training . Federal Ministry of Youth Development, Nigeria

#### **Skills**

E-commerce • WooCommerce • WordPress • Web Design • Web Development • Freelancing • Blogging Software • Content Management • Small Business Management • Business Strategy

#### **Honors & Awards**

Ideal Student Award - Loral International Secondary School

Apr 2011

Honorary Certificate issued to appreciate exemplary students who have been consistently cultured ,refined ,composed ,worthy of emulation in terms of conduct and have been consistent at being Academically sound in Achieving excellent results and Competition feats

Man'O'War Badge - Federal Ministry of Youth Development, Nigeria

Apr 2011

Honored and badged as a distinguished and competent youth Leader who excelled in the training program